Guide to the King County Nurses Association Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
King County Nurses Association records
1908-1990
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
3049
King County Nurses Association (King County, Wash.)
39.9 cubic feet 35 boxes and 2 vertical files
Records of the professional nursing association of King County, Washington
The King County Nurses Association (KCNA) is a professional association of registered nurses, established in 1903 as the King County Graduate Nurses Association and renamed in 1951. It is affiliated on the state and national levels with the Washington State Nurses Association and the American Nurses Association. While the Washington State Nurses Association, of which KCNA is affiliated, functions as both a professional association and a union that collectively bargains for its members, KCNA functions primarily as a professional association that engages in advocacy work. KCNA also maintains a registry of its members and makes referrals to hospitals in need of nursing staff and provides continuing education opportunities for its members, collaborates with other health organizations in King County, and is active in lobbying activities.
Directors of the KCNA:
Julia O. Crose, approx. 1950s-1960s
Margaret Scharnickel, 1970s
Alma Ware, approx. 1980s-1990s
Organized into 5 accessions.
Accession No. 3049-001, King County Nurses Association records, 1908-1978
Accession No. 3049-002, King County Nurses Association records, 1957-1978
Accession No. 3049-003, King County Nurses Association records, 1937-1987
Accession No. 3049-004, King County Nurses Association records, 1959-1989
Accession No. 3049-005, King County Nurses Association records, approximately 1970-1990
Correspondence, minutes, reports, newsletters, financial and membership records, organizational features, committee files, photographs, grant files, and legal documents. There is more detailed description for some of the individual accessions in the scope and content note at the accession level of the finding aid.
Forms part of the Labor Archives of Washington.
Open to all users, but access to portions of the collection are restricted. Contact Special Collections for more details.
King County Nurses Association photograph collection (PH Coll 0091)
Washington State Nurses Association records, Accession No. 1385-009
Washington State Graduate Nurses Association bulletins, Accession No. 5234-001
Crose, Julia O.; Faber, Hilke D.; Kenyon, Virginia; Scharnickel, Margaret; Ware, Alma Miller; Spaulding, Margaret$vTrials, litigation, etc.; American Nurses' Association; King County (Wash.). Health Planning Council; King County Emergency Service Coordinating Council; King County Nurses Association (King County, Wash.)$vArchives; Puget Sound Health Systems Agency; Spaulding, Margaret; University of Washington School of Nursing; Washington State Nurses Association; University of Washington$vTrials, litigation, etc.; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Medicine and Health
- King County Nurses Association records, 1908-1978; 3049-001; 13.68 cubic feet 12 boxes
  Correspondence, minutes, reports, newsletter, membership and financial records.
  Open to all users.
  Records stored offsite; advance notice required for use.
  Donated by the Association, 11/27/1979.
  - HISTORICAL AND ORGANIZATIONAL MATERIALS, 1908-1976; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1-1/5)
    - Historical Documents, 1908-1917 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Organizational Features (Part 1 of 2), 1910, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Organizational Features (Part 2 of 2) - Includes Bylaws, 1968-1976 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Historical Documents, 1921-1937 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - 50th Anniversary Booklet: King County Nurses Association, Inc. District No. 2, Washington State Nurses Association, 1953 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - CORRESPONDENCE, 1903-1977; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/6-1/26)
    - History and Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - General Correspondence, 1922-1934 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - General Correspondence, 1903-1915 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - American Journal of Nursing Correspondence, 1963-1970 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - King County Medical Society Correspondence, 1951-1965 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Legislative Correspondence, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Nursing Practice Correspondence, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Professional Credential and Personnel Service Correspondence, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Seattle Local-Unit Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box-folder 1/14)
    - Post Office Correspondence, 1949-1958 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Payroll Information (Plan #7) State Office Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Washington State Nurses Association and American Nurses Association Dues, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Correspondence (Part 1 of 3), 1975 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Correspondence (Part 2 of 3), 1975 (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Correspondence (Part 3 of 3), 1975 (Box-folder 1/20)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box-folder 1/21)
    - Correspondence (Part 1 of 3), 1976 (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Correspondence (Part 2 of 3), 1976 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Correspondence (Part 3 of 3), 1976 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Correspondence (Part 1 of 2), 1977 (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Correspondence (Part 2 of 2), 1977 (Box-folder 1/26)
  - SUBJECT FILES, 1946-1972; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/27-3/36)
    - American Nurses Association Dues, 1966-1972 (Box-folder 1/27)
    - American Nurses Association Field Services, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 1/28)
    - American Nurses Association Structure and Functions, 1962-1966 (Box-folder 1/29)
    - Annual District Report to State, 1946-1969 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Annual Membership Report, 1958-1970 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Annual Report - Executive Secretary and Treasurer, 1948-1970 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Annual District Reports (Part 1 of 3), 1953-1965 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Annual District Reports (Part 2 of 3), 1953-1965 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Annual District Reports (Part 3 of 3), 1953-1965 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Be Involved Nurse, 1969 (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Bellevue Community College, 1965 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Bills Paid (Part 1 of 2), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Bills Paid (Part 2 of 2), 1967-1968 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - King County Nurses Association, 1970 (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Postal Instant Press, 1970 (Box-folder 2/10)
    - Blood Bank Pool, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Building and Library Fund: Return of Letters, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Building and Library Fund: Memorials, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Council of Planning Affiliates (Part 1 of 2), 1967-1971 (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Council of Planning Affiliates (Part 2 of 2), 1967-1971 (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Washington State Council on Aging, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Directory of Institutional Members - Continuing Care Services, 1970 (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Community Healthy Week, 1968 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Directory, 1969 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Disaster Information, 1966 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Office Economic Opportunity, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Economic Security (Part 1 of 2), 1946-1951 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Economic Security (Part 2 of 2), 1946-1951 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Employment Contract, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Economic Security Contracts, 1970 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Marketing and Equipment, 1967 (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Economic Security (Part 1 of 2), 1947-1969 (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Economic Security (Part 2 of 2), 1947-1969 (Box-folder 2/28)
    - Economic Security Program and Information Statistics, 1956-1966 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Employment Standards, 1966 (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Economic Security and Role of the District Association (Part 1 of 2), 1959-1970 (Box-folder 2/31)
    - Economic Security and Role of the District Association (Part 1 of 2), 1959-1970 (Box-folder 2/32)
    - Economic Security Contracts, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 2/33)
    - Budget, 1970 (Box-folder 2/34)
    - Education Fund: Gifts / Scholarships, 1969 (Box-folder 2/35)
    - Confidential Evaluation Form (Blank), Undated (Box-folder 2/36)
    - Exchange Nurse Material, 1963-1966 (Box-folder 2/37)
    - Personnel Policies, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 2/38)
    - Applications for Executive Director, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 2/39)
    - Executive Director Job Description, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 2/40)
    - Facts on Nursing, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 2/41)
    - Headquarters Application, 1971 (Box-folder 2/42)
    - Headquarters Personnel Policies, 1970 (Box-folder 2/43)
    - Human Rights: Seattle Medical Community, 1969 (Box-folder 2/44)
    - Insurance, 1964-1970 (Box-folder 2/45)
    - Insurance: Fidelity Bond, 1958-1969 (Box-folder 2/46)
    - Insurance Information: North American Insurance Co, American Nurses Association Liability, 1958-1968 (Box-folder 2/47)
    - Liability Insurance: American Nurses Association (Globe Indemnity), 1971 (Box-folder 2/48)
    - Installation of Officers, 1955-1966 (Box-folder 2/49)
    - Inventory of Professional Registered Nurses, 1957-1965 (Box-folder 2/50)
    - Job Descriptions and Performance Review Instrument, 1955-1970 (Box-folder 2/51)
    - Job Descriptions (Part 1 of 2), 1963-1969 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Job Descriptions (Part 1 of 2), 1963-1969 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Legal Files, 1946-1971 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Legal Implications - Nursing Practice, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Library Information, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Department of Licenses Annual Report, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Licensed Practical Nurses Information, 1950-1969 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Licensed Practical Nurses Licenses Department, 1960-1965 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Licensed Practical Nurses Application, 1964 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Licensed Practical Nurses Rejected Applicants, 1968 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Licensed Practical Nurses Forms and Policies, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Licensed Professional Nurses Laws, 1948-1969 (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Washington State Nurses Association Fund Information, 1972 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Manpower Development and Training Act of 1962, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Medicare Information, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Memorials Information, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 3/16)
    - Metropolitan Building Company Regarding Lease, 1950-1964 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Nursing Practice, Code, Roles, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Orders Supplies, 1957-1970 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - King County Nurses Association Policies, 1969 (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Professional Nurses Day, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Professional Nurses Week, 1965 (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Professional Nurses Week, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Professional Nurses Week, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Professional Nurses Week, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Puget Sound Health Planning Council, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Registry Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Registry Evaluation, 1943-1971 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Tax Information, 1955-1970 (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Newsletters, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Newsletters, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Newsletters, 1950-1953 (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Newsletters, 1956-1963 (Box-folder 3/33)
    - Newsletters (Part 1 of 2), 1963-1968 (Box-folder 3/34)
    - Newsletters (Part 2 of 2), 1963-1968 (Box-folder 3/35)
    - Newsletters, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 3/36)
  - CONFERENCES, REPORTS, AND MINUTES, 1902-1971; SERIES IV (Box-folder 4/1-5/18)
    - American Nurses Association Conference State Nursing Association and District Nursing Association, 1965 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - American Nurses Association Executive Director Conference Summaries, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - American Nurses Association Research and Statistics Program, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 4/3)
    - American Nurses Association Concerns in Geriatric Health Insurance, 1965 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Nursing Association Annual Reports, 1923-1940 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Nursing Notes: Selma Rogers, 1936 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Head Nurse Duties and Meeting Minutes, 1948-1962 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - E.A.C.T. Section Minutes, 1953-1963 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - King County Nurses Association Finance Committee, 1950-1960 (Box-folder 4/9)
    - General Duty Unit Representatives, 1950-1965 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - General Duty Minutes and Rules, 1957-1964 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - General Staff Section Minutes, 1949-1954 (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Occupational Health Section Minutes, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Industrial Section Minutes and Rules, 1947-1959 (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Nursing Service Administrator Minutes and Rules, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 4/15)
    - State Committee Nomination Material, 1965 (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Office Nurse Section Minutes and Rules, 1951-1962 (Box-folder 4/17)
    - King County Nurses Association Program Committee Minutes, 1950-1967 (Box-folder 4/18)
    - Audit Reports, 1954-1971 (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Public Health Section Meeting Minutes, 1943-1963 (Box-folder 4/20)
    - Task Force Committee to Study the Registry, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 4/21)
    - Task Force Committee on Evaluation Forms, 1971 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Records of King County Graduate Nurses Association, 1902-1909 (Box-folder 4/23)
    - Graduate Nurses Association, 1909-1913 (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Graduate Nurses Association, 1913-1921 (Box-folder 4/25)
    - Private Duty Section, 1922-1937 (Box-folder 4/26)
    - Minutes of King County Association of Graduate Nurses, 1921-1932 (Box-folder 4/27)
    - Staff Development Meeting Minutes, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Meeting in regards to Bill 104, 1911 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Minutes of Graduate Nurses Association, 1932-1939 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Telephone Users League, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Board of Directors Records, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Committees and Councils, 1938-1942 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Minutes, Treasury and Registrar's Reports (Part 1 of 2), 1940 (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Minutes, Treasury and Registrar's Reports (Part 2 of 2), 1941 (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Written Meeting Accounts, 1940-1959 (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Minutes, Treasury and Registrar's Reports (Part 1 of 2), 1941-1943 (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Minutes, Treasury and Registrar's Reports (Part 2 of 2), 1941-1943 (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Minutes, Treasury and Registrar's Reports (Part 1 of 2), 1944-1945 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Minutes, Treasury and Registrar's Reports (Part 2 of 2), 1944-1945 (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Minutes, Treasury and Registrar's Reports (Part 1 of 2), 1945-1950 (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Minutes, Treasury and Registrar's Reports (Part 2 of 2), 1945-1950 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Board and District Meeting Reports (Part 1 of 2), 1961-1965 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Board and District Meeting Reports (Part 2 of 2), 1961-1965 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Board Meeting, 1969 (Box-folder 5/18)
  - FINANCIAL MATERIALS, 1963-1972; SERIES V (Box-folder 5/19-7/33)
    - Finance and Membership Dues Information, 1968 (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Budget Amount, Plans, and Proposals, 1970 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - District Reports, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Finance Committee - Budget Treasurer Reports, 1939-1955 (Box-folder 5/22)
    - District and Section Accounts (Part 1 of 2), 1957-1961 (Box-folder 5/23)
    - District and Section Accounts (Part 2 of 2), 1957-1961 (Box-folder 5/24)
    - District Account Checks and Deposits, 1969 (Box-folder 5/25)
    - Printing and Traveling Costs and Estimates, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 5/26)
    - Washington State Nurses Association and King County Nurses Association Payroll Deductions (Part 1 of 2), 1969 (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Washington State Nurses Association and King County Nurses Association Payroll Deductions (Part 2 of 2), 1969 (Box-folder 5/28)
    - Financial Report and Budget Proposals, 1969 (Box-folder 5/29)
    - Auburn General, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Ballard Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Boeing Company, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Blood Bank, 1971 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Burien General, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Cabrini, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Children's Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Doctor's Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Evergreen Hospital, 1972 (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Fircrest, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Firland, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Group Health Cooperative, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Harborview Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Highline Community College, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 6/14)
    - King County Nurses Association Invoices, 1972 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Madison Convalescent Centers Deductions, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Seattle Nurse School Deductions, 1972 (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Northwest Hospital Deductions and Dues, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Northgate Hospital Deductions, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Overlake Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/20)
    - Providence Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Seattle General Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Riverton General Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Seattle Health, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Standring Memorial Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Swedish Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/26)
    - University of Washington, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/27)
    - Valley General Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/28)
    - Virginia Mason Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/29)
    - Waldo General Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/30)
    - West Seattle General Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 6/31)
    - Payment Plans, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 6/32)
    - Washington State Nurses Association Receipts, 1972 (Box-folder 6/33)
    - Financial Records (Part 1 of 5), 1964-1968 (Box-folder 6/34)
    - Financial Records (Part 2 of 5), 1968-1969 (Box-folder 6/35)
    - Financial Records (Part 3 of 5), 1970 (Box-folder 6/36)
    - Financial Records (Part 4 of 5), 1970 (Box-folder 6/37)
    - Financial Records (Part 5 of 5), 1969 (Box-folder 6/38)
    - Membership Payment Record, 1970 (Box-folder 6/39)
    - Ruby J. Robbins Financial Booklet, 1963 (Box-folder 6/40)
    - Payroll Book, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 6/41)
    - IRS, 1964 (Box-folder 6/42)
    - Financial Statements and Records, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 6/43)
    - Receipt Records, 1968 (Box-folder 6/44)
    - Checks (Booklet), 1968 (Box-folder 6/45)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 6/46)
    - Checks (Booklet), 1967 (Box-folder 6/47)
    - Receipts (Booklet), 1967 (Box-folder 6/48)
    - Receipts, 1967 (Box-folder 6/49)
    - Employment and Unemployment Security, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Nurse Registry and Financial Statements, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Receipts, 1964 (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Checks, 1964 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Checks, 1966 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Membership, 1965 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Membership, 1966 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Receipts, 1966 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Checks, 1965 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Receipts, 1965 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Ledger, 1963 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Receipts and Checks (Part 1 of 2), 1963 (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Receipts and Checks (Part 2 of 2), 1963 (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Employment and Unemployment Security, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Withholding Tax Form 941, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Federal Income Tax, 1940-1959 (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Withholding Tax Form 941, 1959-1970 (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Budget Request, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Financial District Report, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Audit Information Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Finance Budget, 1955-1961 (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Federal Withholding and Unemployment Taxes, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 7/22)
    - General Income and Expenses, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 7/23)
    - Professional Registry Receipts, 1970 (Box-folder 7/24)
    - District Receipts, 1970 (Box-folder 7/25)
    - Professional Registry - Registry Checks, 1970 (Box-folder 7/26)
    - Professional Registry - Income and Expenses, 1970 (Box-folder 7/27)
    - Payroll Book, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 7/28)
    - District Expenses, 1970 (Box-folder 7/29)
    - Professional Registry - Finances, 1971 (Box-folder 7/30)
    - Payroll Deductions, 1968 (Box-folder 7/31)
    - Personal Property Tax, 1934-1971 (Box-folder 7/32)
    - Withholding Tax Form 941, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 7/33)
  - REGISTRY, 1955-1970; SERIES VI (Box-folder 8/1-9/23)
    - Individual LPN and RN files, 1955-1970 (Box-folder Box 8)
    - Registry Information, 1955-1972 (Box-folder Box 9)
  - MEMBERSHIP RECORD CARE FILES, 1955-1970; SERIES VII (Box-folder 10-11)
    - Membership Record Care File (Part 1 of 2), 1955-1970 (Box-folder Box 10)
    - Membership Record Care File (Part 2 of 2), 1955-1970 (Box-folder Box 11)
  - SCRAPBOOKS, 1950-1970; SERIES VIII (Box-folder 12/1-12/7)
    - Guest Book (Red), 1953-1964 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Scrapbook (Red): newspaper clippings, 1950s-1970s (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Scrapbook (Cream): newspaper clippings and photographs, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Photograph: sepia, unidentified female nurse in floor-length nurse's uniform with wimple style hat, long dark cloak. Photographer's mark on bottom: Harris V. Ewing, Washington D.C., Undated (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Scrapbook (Brown): newspaper clippings and photographs (Fragile), 1950s-1970s (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Scrapbook (Brown): newspaper clippings and photographs, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Scrapbook (Burgundy): newspaper clippings, 1950s-1970s (Box-folder 12/7)
- King County Nurses Association records, 1957-1978; 3049-002; 1.14 cubic foot 1 box
  Correspondence, minutes, membership records from 1960-1965, newsletters, press releases, committee files.
  Includes King County Nurses Association Newsletter from 1957-1969.
  Donated by the Association, 8/18/1980.
- King County Nurses Association records, 1937-1987; 3049-003; 7.98 cubic feet 7 boxes and 1 vertical file
  Organizational features, correspondence, minutes, financial records, legal documents, clippings, other record series.
  Includes files on a lawsuit, Margaret Spaulding vs University of Washington, which accused UW of sex-biased salary discrimination against the Nursing faculty.
  View inventory/container list
  Donated by the Association, 6/8/1987.
- King County Nurses Association records, 1959-1989; 3049-004; 9.12 cubic feet 8 boxes and 1 Vertical File
  This accession spans the years 1959-1989 and documents the activities of the King County Nurses Association membership, Executive Board, special interest groups, and committees. Records include correspondence; committee and board meeting agendas, minutes, and meeting motions; convention records from KCNA, the Washington State Nurses Association, and American Nurses Association; financial documents; membership records; press, publicity, and published material from KCNA or affiliated organizations; records from continuing education and other programming KCNA sponsored or participated in; reports; awards nominations; and subject files with information on nursing and other health related issues.
  See the arrangement note for a detailed list of records groups and series. When needed, additional scope and content information is included at the subgroup or series level in the box/folder inventory.
  The collection is arranged into 15 subgroups based on the part of KCNA that the records originated from, and then into series and subseries when applicable. Subgroup 1 contains the main office files of the organization while the remaining subgroups contain records created and/or used by the Executive Board, specific committees, or organizations that included representatives from KCNA.
  The arrangement is as follows:
  SUBGROUP 1: KING COUNTY NURSES ASSOCIATION OFFICE FILES, 1965-1989